MICHAEL BUCHANAN

Software Developer

Cincinnati, OH | (859) 835-3089

michaelbuchanan23@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/michaelbuchanan23 6

github.com/michaelbuchanan23

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Developer transitioning to software development from practicing law. Formerly a student at Cincy Code IT's .Net Development Boot Camp at Max Technical Training. Strengths include project management, client communication, meticulous attention to detail, logical problem solving, and the ability to learn and adapt quickly. Recognized for learning new technology quickly and then using the technology to make process improvements that save both time and money. Looking to utilize my skills to find a job as a software developer.

Technical skills:

- C#/.Net
- Entity Framework
- MVC Razor
- WebAPI

- JavaScript/jQuery
- Bootstrap
- Scrum Certified/Agile
- Git/GitHub

- SQL Server
- TypeScript
- Angular 6
- HTML/CSS

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

MAX Technical Training/Cincy Code IT | Mason, OH

.Net/C# Boot Camp

Summer 2018

- Completed MAX/Cincy Code IT's.Net Development Boot Camp comprising 11 weeks and 440 hours of
 concentrated, advanced, and deeply engaging full stack software development. The camp combined in-class
 instruction, hands-on programming, individual based project work, and mentoring to ensure a thorough
 comprehension of coding and concepts.
- Backend development included SQL and C#.
- Frontend development included Angular 6, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, and TypeScript. Design included HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap.
- Created a full, operational purchase request system. Backend database is constructed with C# using Entity
 Framework to a SQL Database. Frontend is developed using Angular/TypeScript. Web design used HTML,
 CSS, and Bootstrap.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

AMERICAN LEGAL PUBLISHING CORPORATION | Cincinnati, OH

2016-2018

National provider of services to municipalities and counties including ordinance codification and supplementation.

Legal Editor

Member of the New Code Team responsible for organizing materials and ordinances in order to codify said material in a variety of formats for municipalities and counties across the country.

- Edited/managed word processing files to create codifications that organized municipal codes and local legislation by subject matter.
- Performed routine cite checks, editing checks, and comparisons to state and federal law.
- Conducted detailed proofreading, ensuring excellent grammar, spelling, and formatting.
- Updated legal material by removing repealed or obsolete ordinances and adding new codified ordinances.
- Conducted consultative meetings with clients to provide solutions to codification issues.

KEATING MUETHING & KLEKAMP PLL | Cincinnati, OH

2011-2016

Legal firm with practice areas in banking, insurance, and financial services; business representation and transactions; commercial finance and reorganization; employee benefits and executive compensation; insurance coverage and litigation; intellectual property; labor and employment; litigation; private client services; and real estate law.

Attorney

Gained a broad knowledge of regulatory compliance by working on a wide variety of qui tam matters. Served as the firm's lead on discovery work with several hundred thousand documents for a case that involved the BP oil spill. Provided legal advice, opinions, and analysis to clients and potential clients on pending and potential qui tam and other legal matters. Reviewed/analyzed contracts in performing due diligence for corporate mergers.

- Handpicked out of a group of 30 other attorneys to work on a shareholder suit regarding the BP oil spill.
- Regulatory compliance experience includes areas of law such as duty tax, durable medical equipment, securities fraud, Medicare fraud, government contracts, Stark Law, and the Anti-Kickback Statute.
- Made case/client recommendations via written memorandums and meetings based on research of a wide variety of legal issues and areas of law.
- Case management and development skills include initial client interviews and screening, researching potential
 claims, developing case strategy, documentary evidence review, background and asset checks, consulting with
 co-counsel, and client management.
- Discovery experience includes summarizing depositions, identifying and organizing documentary evidence for use in depositions, motion practice, and trial, and extensive document review related to securities fraud involving the BP oil spill.

WESTERN & SOUTHERN FINANCIAL GROUP | Cincinnati, OH

2006-2008

A diversified family of financial services companies including life insurance and annuities.

Customer Service Analyst | Annuity Analyst

Interacted with clients via writing letters, talking on the phone, and emailing on a daily basis. These interactions were primarily regarding life insurance and annuities sales and service.

- Awarded a Special Merit Award for creating a centralized and searchable database containing company policies and training materials. This database streamlined solutions to problem areas in training new employees and, by the company's own estimate, saved the company tens of thousands of dollars.
- Renegotiated annuity contracts, helping to conserve \$10M+ of business in fixed and variable annuities in 2007.
- Obtained an Ohio Health and Life Insurance License.

CERTIFICATIONS

Professional Scrum Foundations Two-Day Course Professional Scrum Master Certified (PSM I)

EDUCATION

Juris Doctor | Salmon P. Chase College of Law | Graduated 2010 Associate Editor, Northern Kentucky Law Review | Graduated in 2 ½ years

BA, English

University of Kentucky | Graduated 2004

PROJECTS

Overview:

The projects below consist of Techies for Good, personal projects, and code completed during the .Net Boot Camp during the summer of 2018.

Purchase Request System

2018

While attending .Net Boot Camp we were challenged to create an app that would utilize nearly all of the skills we learned. Therefore, I created, as part of my Capstone Project, a Purchase Request System (PRS). It is an application that provides users with the ability to request items they need. Each request can contain multiple different lines that specify the product and the quantity of that product and utilizes a host of technical skills as shown below.

Technical skills used: C#, SQL, Entity Framework Angular 6, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap GitHub Backend: https://github.com/michaelbuchanan23/PRSServer GitHub Frontend: https://github.com/michaelbuchanan23/PRSClient

Legalnook 2011

While attending law school I had poor results trying to find case briefs and outlines online. To fix this problem, and offer law students a better solution, I created a website with a searchable database to view/upload case briefs and outlines. The website has been up and running for several years, and I intend on updating it using the new development skills I acquired while attending the .Net Boot Camp.

Technical skills used: PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Adobe Dreamweaver, jQuery URL: http://www.legalnook.com

PigPen (Pig Dice Game Variation)

2018

Variation on the game of Pig Dice coded entirely in C#. In PigPen the rules are as follows:

- Each turn, a player repeatedly rolls a die until either a 1 is rolled or the player decides to "hold".
 - If the player rolls a 1, they score nothing and it becomes the next player's turn.
 - If the player rolls any other number, it is added to their turn total and the player's turn continues.
 - If a player chooses to "hold", their turn total is added to their score, and it becomes the next player's turn.

In the PigPen variation that I created the player with the highest score after 5 rounds wins the game.

Technical skills used: C#

GitHub: https://github.com/michaelbuchanan23/PigPenMike

Volunteer Signup Web Application

2018

This is a Techies for Good project. Two local nonprofits have asked us to develop an online application that gives their volunteers the ability to sign up for events online. We are currently working with each organization to finalize details of the project.